Alexander Musayev

Date of birth: 17 Jul 1981 E-mail: alex.musayev@gmail.com

Location: Saint-Petersburg, Russia Skype: dreikanter

Education: Higher technical Phone: +7 (905) 266-61-66

Skills and specialization

Ten years of experience in software design and development. Requirements analysis, system architecture, tasks decomposition and estimation, specifications and technical documentation development. UI/UX design and prototyping.

Keeping things in order and transforming the Complex into the Simple.

Programming languages:

- Ruby (1.9-2.1; web apps/services, rest apis, cli tools, deployment automation; rails 3-4.2, sinatra, minitest, rspec, factorygirl, capistrano, mina, devise, haml, slim, guard, unicorn, god, eye, spree, code quality analysis tools).
- **Python** (2.6-3.4; cli tools for data processing and automation; packaging; django, jinja, argparse, logging, unit tests).
- C# (.net 1.1-4.0, winforms/wpf, wcf, spring.net, moq, xunit, nunit, wix, msmq, zeromq, log4net, nlog, 3rd party UI components).
- o **JavaScript** (jquery, jquery ui, angular, require.js, handlebars, underscore, coffeescript, chrome extensions api).
- Databases: postgresql, mysql, sqlite, microsoft sql server (std, express, ce), redis.
- **Web-related:** html, css, less, sass, twitter bootstrap (2, 3), and some other web frameworks. Servers: nginx, apache.
- **Version control:** git is the personal preference; also has experience with svn, p4, tfs.
- **IDE and favorite tools:** sublime text, jetbrains pycharm, microsoft visual studio since 6.0; visio, linux shell (bash, zsh, core tools); photoshop.
- Fluent English and native Russian language.

Interests

Awesome products development, distributed systems architecture, web technologies, UI design, open source.

GitHub

Most of my personal projects are published at GitHub (libraries and tools for system automation, text processing, web content management; there are also few google chrome extensions and some more) \rightarrow http://github.com/dreikanter

Experience

System architect, backend developer

Softin.co, Saint-Petersburg Dec 2013 — Present time

Responsibility:

- Distributed systems design.
- Web-apps/services development.

Senior software developer (Outsourcing)

Luxoft, Saint-Petersburg Jan 2012 — Dec 2013

- Participation in enterprise-grade projects development (HP, Modular Mining).
- New features development and existing codebase support.
- · Technical interviews conduction.

Software developer (Outsourcing, R&D)

Lanit-Tercom, Saint-Petersburg Aug 2008 — Dec 2011

Responsibility:

- Enterprise software development (desktop applications and web services), testing, deployment and support (.NET/C#, PL/SQL, Java, Flex).
- Requirements analysis, tasks decomposition and estimation, creating specifications and project documentation.
- UI prototyping and development, UI logic formalization.

Achievements:

- Analytical information system for thermal power plants for Infoenergo Ltd. (Russia).
- Web-based media management system for DTS Medien AG (Germany).
- Medical data management system for Huntington Hospital (California, USA) / dbMotion Ltd. (Israel).

Software developer (R&D)

SZMA LLC, Saint-Petersburg Aug 2006 — Dec 2009

Responsibility:

- Architecture design for distributed software.
- Requirements analysis, specification drafting and project documentation.
- Software development, testing, deployment and support (C#, Matlab, MQL, MySQL, PHP).
- Technical documentation and user manuals drafting.

Achievements:

- Web service for financial data collection, verification, and analysis.
- Middleware for Matlab integration with Metaguotes MetaTrader (trading platform).

Post graduate student

SPIIRAS, Saint-Petersburg Dec 2004 — Dec 2008

Responsibility:

- Research in the field of mathematical modeling, scientific conferences participation.
- Participating in development of Computer-aided Modeling System for the Large-scale Social Economic Projects (Russian Foundation for Basic Research grant).
- Experimental software development (C#).
- Training course development for third-year university students.

Achievements:

• A number of publications in science magazines and institute proceedings on mathematical modeling and enterprise automation.

Professor assistant

SPb UWC, Saint-Petersburg Oct 2006 — Jul 2008

Responsibility:

- Training course development for university students.
- Lecturing and running workshops on C++ programming, seminars organization on enterprise software development.
- Exams admission, participating in the examination committee for the "Information Security" specialty.

Achievements:

- Practical programming experience in high-level languages for about 50 university students.
- Lecture notes on C++ programming.

Software developer

7+11 Company Ltd., Saint-Petersburg
Jul 2003 — Oct 2007

Responsibility:

- Distributed systems design and developing for enterprise automation and monitoring systems.
- Data collection and visualization systems development.
- Embedded software testing, deployment and support.
- Requirements analysis, technical documentation.
- Office LAN administration (25 workplaces).

Achievements:

- Launched automated control systems for VTB Bank headquarters, Kronverk Business Center and a number of other office and residential buildings in Saint-Petersburg.
- Kilowatt-hours and gigacalories saved by control algorithms optimization for embedded systems.

Education

Higher: St. Petersburg State University of Airspace Instrumentation (SUAI)

Department of Automatic Control Systems

Specialty: Automatic Control and Information Processing Systems

1998 - 2004

Postgraduate: St. Petersburg Institute for Informatics and Automation of Russian

Academy of Sciences (SPIIRAS)

Specialty: Mathematical and Software Support of Computers,

Complex Systems and Networks

2004 - 2008

Trainings/certificates

oDesk test: Ruby, Ruby on Rails.

Smarterer.com: Python, Ruby, Ruby on Rails (master level).

Brainbench certificates: C, HTML.

- Careerlab certificate: High Level Architecture Design with UML.
- Artyom Gorbunov's Educational Center certificate: User Experience design and Information Visualization.
- System Analysis School certificate for software requirements development course.
- Luxoft course completion certificates on system analysis and software architecture.

Miscellaneous

- Traveling passport is available, inland and abroad business trips experience.
- U.S. visa.